Yangjun Wang

yangjun.wang90@gmail.com

(+358)50-4619144

wangyangjun.github.io

Summary

I have more than two years working experience of software development. I am familiar with web development and data analysis technologies. Recently, I have finished my master thesis in Aalto university – benchmark stream processing systems. I think I have good understanding of big data technologies, especially stream processing technologies like Storm, Flink, Spark Streaming and Kafka. I am looking for a full-time job related to **big data** technologies.

Education

Work

Experience

Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

Master of Science, School of Science

Major: Foundations of Advanced Computing

2013.09 - 2016.06

Thesis: StreamBench – Stream processing system benchmark

Hunan University

Changsha, China 2008.09 - 2012.06

Bachelor of Engineer, School of Software Engineering

Major: Software Engineering

Software Engineer Eniram Oy

Espoo, Finland

• Web Software Development(React, Mocha)

2016.05 - present

• Docker, Robot test

Master thesis Aalto University

Espoo, Finland

• Research streaming process systems

2015.10 - 2016.04

- Development(Java, Python)
- Setup and maintenance experiment clusters

Junior Software Developer Luxus Oy

Helsinki, Finland

• Web Software Development(Node.js+Express+MongoDb)

2014.05 - 2015.02

- Windows Phone App Development
- Azure Cloud Service(Web Role) Development

Junior Software Engineer JD.COM

Chengdu, China

• Web Software Development(J2EE)

2012.07 - 20 13.08

• Data Analysis (Hadoop/hive)

Projects

Skype Gift , Office365Gift, SwitchGift (Client: Microsoft) This propose of this project is to promote Skype campaign for new Lumia users. It is consist of a WP mobile app and a server. The server side needs communicate with several Microsoft servers to handle high security requirement.

Helsinki, Finland 2014.07 - 2014.11

- Client: WP mobile application
- Server: Azure Web Service, Azure TableStorage
- Analysis: Spark SQL in HDInsight, NodeJs and D3.js for visualization

JMA (JD Mobile Analysis)

Chengdu, China 2013.01 - 2013.08

JMA is a general, real-time, professional analysis tool of user's behavior. JMA could help mobile app developers analysis the users' properities and behaviors, so that the mobile app developers avoid the shortages and make better products.

- Web Development(J2EE) and Data Analysis(Hadoop/Hive)
- WP SDK for collection data from mobile devices
- Data collection service

Online Courses

• BerkeleyX: CS100.1x Introduction to Big Data with Apache Spark

• BerkeleyX: CS105x Introduction to Apache Spark

IT Skills

Languages: Java, Javascript, C#, Python

Skills: Hadoop/Spark/Storm/Flink, Azure, ASP.NET, Maven, Spring+Struts,

Node.js, AngularJs, .net, jQuery, CSS, Mysql, MongoDb

<u>Tools:</u> IntelliJ IDEA, Sublime Text3, Git